So your challenge, should you choose to accept it, is go ahead and look at either the way the task card is or the planner card.
And so those you'll see they're being looped through, if you look for the V4 inside of the app.
They got some pretty complex things going on there.
So go ahead and see if you can refactor that out so that you're using slots to basically have some actions, some of the text being rendered.
And then play around with it, see if you can go ahead and render the content differently, rearrange it as you see fit through the parent,
through the parent rather than the child.
And then if it should make sense, go ahead and try using the use slots helper function if you think it makes sense to hide certain things and whatnot.
Our goal here is to create a planner card, it's called a new planner card at the time.
Because basically if we take a look at, let's see if we go to V4,
I had a weak, a sea reflection page, settings page, see lots of opportunity for refactoring, lots of ripe opportunities.
But anyhow, weak detail page, although, oh, here's a planner page, I jumped all the way, okay.
And then we want this one in particular, because this here, as we can see, is basically the card that displays, let's correspond this with overseeing.
This corresponds with this particular card right here.
So if we're taking a look at this, we can see that it's, I would say, roughly broken out into.
Yeah, it's a, if we're being generous, or being, or yeah, we could say two sections here, because we have the tasks here that are basically showing all the stuff here.
And then we have basically stuff about the weak here.
So, and then I would say, though, this is a little bit maybe more meta.
So arguably, you could make a slot here that, like, if you don't want to display this, that could be a choice.
I think for now, I think, so what's going to do that, just to keep it, just give us a little bit more options.
And so what I would do here is, all right, so let me take this, and then.
Boop, boop, boop, boop.
All right, let's close this stuff to me, it's easier to track.
All right.
The first thing we're going to want to do is we're going to create a new component.
And I'll call it new planner card.
Because this one is going to look different from the other one.
It's kind of the whole point of this exercise.
So I'm going to copy this entire thing.
Actually, let's just collapse it that'll probably be faster.
Copy this.
Oh.
And then drop that in here.
Okay, lots of squigglies, lots and lots of squigglies.
So first thing first, we definitely don't need this.
If statement at the top.
And then select it, we test.
So that's something we're going to need to pass.
It seems.
So define props already.
And then.
So here we have an option.
By the way, to, I think this is probably supposed to be an array.
So let's see.
Yep, this is a task array.
So, you know, for those, if you are in need to type here, this is one of the benefits.
And then the main objective is that you do get sort of cleaner type definitions.
So understand what you're expecting.
So I'm expecting an array.
So just to do, do, do, do.
So we just call it an array for now.
We'll keep it real simple from a type perspective.
Type array.
And then, uh, require true.
Okay.
And then basically.
So you might be thinking, okay.
Then I'm just going to need this task.
And then we'll call it, we'll call it today.
Uh, I would propose something to consider is.
I find that one off errors by the letter S happened a lot in terms of coding.
It's just easy to get that off.
So I actually usually like to just make arrays.
I just, just a pen list instead.
This is a bit cleaner.
Uh, you just get fewer one off errors.
Again, this is not a must do or anything.
Just something thought I'd share.
And then, okay.
So we have a task.
Uh, at this point, these are type errors.
We're not going to find the type strip.
That is not the point of this course.
Uh, but I think.
I have, though, if I could.
Let me see if I can cheat this a little bit.
Uh, prop type.
So.
There is a way I believe.
This, let's see if this will work though.
Oh, I am totally wrong.
Whoops.
Not here.
Da, da, da, da.
That did work.
Okay.
So a little type script, snippet.
Uh, for you all to see.
is that, again, if you're defining a props
normally via composition API, this is what you're using.
And then there is this ability in type
of call to basically to typecast if I remember that correctly.
And so the as basically tells it like, hey,
I know what it's supposed to be.
And then so you need to use this prop type helper
from view that then you pass in the type it's supposed to be.
That's all that's happening here.
So I'll leave that snippet in here just because I think it's a nice one to know.
It's just, again, just a little bit of type script.
And we didn't go over this earlier, but there is like,
all of the types that we are being using this code base
should be managed mostly in here.
So you can see here that all our tasks are defined right here.
And so again, if you need to type script interface,
it's basically just an rather than a type
that's just like a bunch of strings or kind of like standard object,
a standard values, interface usually represents an object.
And there's a whole debate between types and interface
of when it comes to objects.
But generally speaking, people use interfaces
when it comes to objects from what I've seen.
All right, so anyways, that little detour explained.
Okay, so we got that in cool, cool, cool.
And so, all right, so now we mentioned that we want to break this up
into like, I set three parts, but let's see,
this part's being looped.
This is a button to expand stuff.
Huh, why do I feel like, okay, icon is expanded.
Three more tasks show less VIF.
Why do I feel like I miss something VIFs
like the weak task border top?
This looked like it's related.
Yep, toggle a task list.
Okay, but what we can do is to start though,
let's just do this.
We have this like the task, the duh, duh,
then we have tasks here, task list.
And then is task list expanded?
Let's just replace all these first, is task list expanded.
Okay, so then what we're cleaning here
is we have something defining the visibility of something via here.
So we can go ahead and then say is expanded.
Is probably what I would go with, is a boolean,
and then we'll default that to false, just like that.
And then this way it'll be easier.
Now the only tricky part is what is this toggle task list doing?
So we're gonna go back, toggle task list,
and so it looks like it's literally toggled
in whether it's visible or not.
So honestly, that's not something we need to pass down.
That is something theoretically
we can just click on our own.
So in that regard, I just gonna make a toggle expanded,
and then we're just gonna say,
this is where it gets a little bit tricky.
Because she should not be mutating your props.
So if I wanna just, I'll follow that, follow that for now.
And so we can say, we'll import computed from you.
And then I'll say, oh, this is, this is mine.
I don't wanna do this.
Okay, is visible equals rough, false,
I think that in, then again, if we're doing this
like the proper lifecycle way,
you're basically saying that, hey,
when the component is mounted,
you're gonna take is visible that value
and set it to the props that is visible.
That's how you would like to, wait, is expanded.
Thank you.
Yep, and so then you have that.
So then we could basically say, is visible, is,
is, is, is, is, is, is, is, is, is,
like that, and then I usually like to put my mounted
a lifecycle hooks at the bottom.
So then we can toggle, expanded, and, yeah,
then we'll do it.
Okay, so then to see that that works,
we can go down to, to, to, to the V4,
when I find it, there it is.
Okay, so we're gonna do, is we're just gonna do
a new planar card here.
And this time we are gonna say the task list,
we know that is like the weak tasks.
And then I think that's the only thing that I required
is expanded, yep, default false.
And let's see, are we doing anything interesting
with that here?
Hidden is task list expanded.
Okay, so that means we do, in this regard,
we can say, is expanded,
it is equal to is task list expanded like that.
Okay, so then we can refresh,
and then you can see,
fail to resolve component.
Yeah, that would, that will do the trick.
It looks like I dropped it in,
but it did not import because,
and the import type bites me again.
Okay, now we have some other things we're doing with.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
New planar card format time is not a function.
Where is that?
Okay, got it.
Okay.
This will be relevant later,
so we're just gonna copy this.
We know that I write less,
I am acknowledging that this is not dry code.
This is just to also demonstrate
some stuff we're gonna be doing later.
In fact, let me just verify there aren't any other errors.
Nope, okay, we go.
Is expanded by access.n.to find on the instance.
Ah, but we see here, here we go.
There it is right here.
So it looks like I took just a small segment of it.
And so again, for the sake of just demonstrating
what we did, as far as, in order to practice what we did.
So really, this is the new planar card.
Honestly, I'm just gonna call it body,
because that's really what we just did.
So what are we changing?
Yes, please apply that.
And then a new card,
new planar card, body, new planar card,
new planar card, body, great.
Okay, now that we have that,
then this is where we can practice exactly
what we talked about.
So in this regard, so we could say here in this slot,
this here, we are clearly rendering like a bunch of,
look to save, I did too much.
Da, da, da, da.
I want the slot to wrap around this stuff.
Yes, there you go.
All right, excellent.
And this slot, let's see, we are basically displaying
the list of tasks.
So I can just call this name, task list to be honest.
And then what we can do then is basically say,
hey, look, on this slot, we're gonna provide,
do do do do do, we're gonna provide the task list.
And so in this case, again, this is more for the practice
and not because you've only have access to it already,
but that's what we would do.
We would basically give the slot access to this thing.
And then that way, when you're inside using it.
But, but, but, again, to be clear, this is a little redundant
because of the fact that you have tasks that's already access,
this then gives you access to basically,
and I'll just do it like this just so that we can just show
that some things different.
So two things I did here that I didn't explicitly
explain before in case you're new to it.
One, this here, the pound symbol, is a shorthand for v-slot.
The reason why, and to be clear, it is only applicable on the template,
you cannot use this shorthand anywhere else,
because it's only for v-slot.
Then pre here is a nice little shortcut for basically displaying data
in a nice, like, JSON way.
Because if you did it without the pre and you just did it as p,
you'll see it's very, very unreadable.
So the pre is a nice little legibility thing
that, like, theoretically, can you console log?
Yes, but I sometimes like to see my data on my UI.
So this is something I use a lot, just to make it a little bit more visible.
So yeah, so you can see here, we've exposed it.
And then, yeah, that's basically that.
And then if you really wanted to then practice to use slots,
the way you would do that is you would say,
con-slots equals use slots.
And then we could basically double check it and be like,
hey, look, if the slots.castlists is being used,
then render this, otherwise, do not.
And that kind of combines the two techniques.
And that way you don't have this random spacer.
So I guess, I guess, also worth mentioning for those
if you're new to tailwind CSS, sort of these sort of utilities,
CSS classes, these things basically apply CSS, like, as little.
So this one says space vertically,
I think this is going to be just two units of whatever that is.
That's what that is.